northernlight.com 2018-08-18

# Privacy - Northern Light - Machine learning powered knowledge management

### Onward Transfers to Third Party

In the context of an onward transfer, Northern Light has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. The Northern Light shall remain liable under the Privacy Shield if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the principles of the Privacy Shield, unless the Northern Light proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

### FTC or court order based on non-compliance

If Northern Light becomes subject to an FTC or court order based on non-compliance, Northern Light shall make public any relevant Privacy Shield-related sections of any compliance or assessment report submitted to the FTC, to the extent consistent with confidentiality requirements. The Privacy Shield has established a dedicated point of contact for reporting any problems with compliance. The FTC will give priority consideration to referrals of non-compliance with the principles of the Privacy Shield, and will exchange information regarding referrals with any referring state authorities on a timely basis, subject to existing confidentiality restrictions.

### Compliance Inquiries and Complaints

Northern Light, and our independent recourse mechanism provider, will respond promptly to inquiries and requests for information relating to the Privacy Shield. Northern Light , and our independent recourse mechanism provider, will respond expeditiously to complaints regarding compliance with the principles of the Privacy Shield.

Northern Light is obligated to arbitrate claims, provided that an individual has invoked binding arbitration by delivering notice to the Northern Light and following the procedures and subject to conditions set forth in the Privacy Shield requirements.

### Third Party Partners and Integrations

The Site may contain links to third party the Sites or services, such as third party integrations, co-branded services, or third party-branded services (“Third Party Partners”).  Northern Light does not own or control these Third Party Partners and when you interact with them, you may be providing information directly to the Third Party Partner, Northern Light, or both. These Third Party Partners will have their own rules about the collection, use, and disclosure of information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of the other the Sites you visit.

### Your Rights

You may exercise any of the rights described in this section by sending an email to privacy@NorthernLight.com. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request.

  * Managing Your Information.  If you have created an Account, you may access and update some of your information through your Account settings. You are responsible for keeping your personal information up-to-date.
  * Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Information.  You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information concerning you (and which you cannot update yourself within your account).
  * Data Access and Portability. In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to request copies of your personal information held by us. You may also be entitled to request copies of personal information that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider (where technically feasible).
  * Data Retention and Erasure.  We generally retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for the performance services we provide you from the Site to comply with our legal obligations.  We may store your personal information for longer periods for our own purposes including improving the performance of the Site and other items described above.  If you no longer want us to use your information to provide the Site, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your account. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information: 
    * We may retain some of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety. For example, if we suspend an account for fraud or safety reasons, we may retain certain information from that account to prevent that user or customer from opening a new account in the future.
    * We may retain and use your personal information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations. For example, Northern Light may keep some of your information for tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations.
    * Information you have shared with others (e.g., forum postings) may continue to be publicly visible on the Site, even after your account is cancelled. However, attribution of such information to you will be removed. Additionally, some copies of your information (e.g., log records) may remain in our database, but are disassociated from personal identifiers.
    * Because we maintain redundant copies of the Site to protect from accidental or malicious loss and destruction, residual copies of your personal information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time.
  * Withdrawing Consent and Restriction of Processing.  Where you have expressly provided your consent to the processing of your personal information by Northern Light you may withdraw your consent at any time by deleting your Account settings or by sending a communication to Northern Light specifying which consent you are withdrawing. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal. Additionally, in some jurisdictions, applicable law may give you the right to limit the ways in which we use your personal information, in particular where (i) you contest the accuracy of your personal information; (ii) the processing is unlawful and you oppose the erasure of your personal information; (iii) we no longer need your personal information for the purposes of the processing, but you require the information for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or (iv) you have objected to the processing pursuant to Section 5.6 and pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of Northern Light override your own.
  * Objection to Processing.  In some jurisdictions, applicable law may permit you to legally object to Northern Light’s processing. In these instances, you may require Northern Light not to process your personal information for specific purposes even where such processing is based on legitimate interest. If you object to such processing Northern Light will no longer process your personal information for these purposes unless we can demonstrate a legal basis for doing so or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. At any time, regardless of applicable law, you may object to us processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You may, at any time, ask Northern Light to cease processing your data for these direct marketing purposes by sending an e-mail to [privacy@NorthernLight.com](mailto:privacy@NorthernLight.com).
  * Lodging Complaints.  With respect to GDPR, you have the right to submit complaints about the data processing activities carried out by Northern Light before the appropriate commission in your jurisdiction.  Please seek your own legal counsel or appropriate government agency for instructions.  For complaints unrelated to GDPR, nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to limit your right to file a complaint in the appropriate jurisdiction.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Northern Light commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Northern Light at:

Northern Light Privacy Department  
One Constitution Center  
Boston, MA 02129

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

### Unsubscribe or Opt-Out

All users and/or visitors to the Site have the option to discontinue receiving communication from us and/or reserve the right to discontinue receiving communications by way of email or newsletters. To discontinue or unsubscribe to the Site please send an email that you wish to unsubscribe to unsubscribe@northernlight.com.  If you wish to unsubscribe or opt-out from any third party websites, you must go to that specific website to unsubscribe and/or opt-out.

### Operating Globally

To facilitate our global operations Northern Light may transfer, store, and process your information within our organization and facilities and to third party service providers based in countries in Europe or the United States. Laws in these countries may differ from the laws applicable to your Country of Residence. For example, information collected within the EEA may be transferred, stored, and processed outside of the EEA for the purposes and bases described in this Privacy Policy. Where we transfer, store, and process your personal information outside of the EEA we have ensured that appropriate safeguards are in place to ensure an adequate level of data protection.

  * EU Model Clauses.  If your information is shared with corporate affiliates or third party companies or service providers outside the EEA, we have, prior to sharing your information with such corporate affiliate or third party company or service provider we have a reasonable basis for believing the third party company has an adequate level of data protection. This agreement may incorporate the basis of the EU Model Clauses (a set of clauses issued by the European Commission).
  * California Privacy Rights.  California law permits users and customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those third parties. See the “Contact Us” section for where to send such requests. Northern Light does not share personal information with third parties for its own direct marketing purposes without your prior consent. Accordingly, you can prevent disclosure of your personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes by withholding consent.

### Security

We are continuously implementing and updating administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use to protect your information are firewalls and data encryption, and information access controls. If you know or have reason to believe that your account credentials have been lost, stolen, misappropriated, or otherwise compromised or in case of any actual or suspected unauthorized use of your account, please contact us following the instructions in the Contact Us section below.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Northern Light reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time in accordance with this provision. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site and update the “Last Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We will also provide you with notice of the modification by email at least thirty (30) days before the date the changes become effective. If you disagree with the revised Privacy Policy, you may cancel your Account and stop using the Site. If you do not cancel your Account before the date the revised Privacy Policy becomes effective and stop using the Site, your continued access to or use of the Site will be subject to the revised Privacy Policy.

### Links to Other Web Sites

The Site does contain links to affiliate and other websites. Northern Light does not claim nor accept responsibility for any privacy policies, practices and/or procedures of other such websites. Therefore, we encourage all users and visitors to be aware when they leave our website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. The aforementioned Privacy Policy Agreement applies only and solely to the information collected by the Site.

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Privacy Policy Agreement related to the Site, please feel free to contact us at the following email, telephone number or mailing address.

Email: [privacy@northernlight.com](mailto:privacy@northernlight.com)

Telephone Number:    617 515-5771

Mailing Address:

Northern Light Privacy Department  
One Constitution Center  
Boston, MA 02129
